<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ali Akyol</title>
    <link>https://alicakyol.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://alicakyol.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ali Akyol</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 17:30:49 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://alicakyol.github.io/media/icon_hu8a7e4f2c9e4c48b6bb498a58f150394e_28744_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Ali Akyol</title>
      <link>https://alicakyol.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Long-Term Institutional Investors Prefer Future-Focused CEOs?</title>
      <link>https://alicakyol.github.io/project/paper4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 17:30:49 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicakyol.github.io/project/paper4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Agency theory has long discussed the misalignment between the interests of long-term institutional investors and CEOs. We postulated that future-focused CEOs might mitigate the agency problem as they are more likely to consider long-term goals as more important and invest accordingly. Our analysis drawing on data from 17,983 firm-year observations between 2001 and 2016, however, did not support our initial argumentation. In contrary, it showed a positive relationship between quasi-indexers and investment advisors, both considered as long-term investors, and past-focused CEOs. The possible explanation for this finding draws on the information asymmetry between investors and CEOs. A long-term investment is associated with uncertainty, which prevents the transparency needed to mitigate the information asymmetry. Our study contributes to agency theory and the micro-foundation of strategic management.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyst Experience and Accrual Anomaly: How Do Experienced Analysts Improve Price Efficiency?</title>
      <link>https://alicakyol.github.io/project/paper3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 17:20:46 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicakyol.github.io/project/paper3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We document that the accrual anomaly is substantially mitigated for firms followed by more experienced analysts. We then examine research and monitoring as possible channels through which experience mitigates mispricing. For firms followed by more experienced analysts, we find that forecast revisions and stock prices respond more positively to the accrual component of earnings. We further find that accrual quality is higher in firms followed by more experienced analysts, which holds after using both propensity score matching and exogenous events of brokerage closures and mergers to control for endogeneity. Finally, our results indicate that only years of experience directly covering the firm matter while experience covering other firms is not associated with greater price efficiency. Collectively, our results are consistent with monitoring being the primary mechanism by which experienced analysts reduce accrual mispricing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corporate Gender Culture</title>
      <link>https://alicakyol.github.io/project/paper1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicakyol.github.io/project/paper1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.renee-adams.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Renee B. Adams&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/paulinegrosjeanperso/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pauline A. Grosjean&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We show workplace culture is gendered. We apply computational linguistic models to listed firms’ reports to an Australian gender-equality agency to construct the first systematic measures of ‘corporate gender culture’—firms’ practices pertaining to the treatment of women across seven dimensions, from recruitment and promotion to maternity leave and sexual harassment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our measures reveal that firms treat women systematically differently from men, but also that gender differentiation varies across industry and firm characteristics. The cultural dimension that best predicts women’s representation in corporate leadership is also the one that best predicts firm performance, namely equality of training opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Does the Market React When Shareholders Lose Power?</title>
      <link>https://alicakyol.github.io/project/paper2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 13:07:54 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicakyol.github.io/project/paper2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I examine a decision made by a corporate vote tabulating firm that removed the ability of proposal sponsors to obtain interim vote tally data in exempt solicitation campaigns. The decision by the firm reduced the probability of the implementation of shareholder proposals and I use it to infer whether the market views that shareholder proposals create value. I find that the market’s reaction to the decision was, overall, positive and its reaction increased depending on the type of proposal and its sponsor. The results suggest that some shareholder proposals are not viewed as value creating by the market and indicate that it is important to understand how shareholders get involved in corporate affairs to correctly gauge the benefits and costs of shareholder proposals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;i class=&#34;ai ai-obp  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.law.duke.edu/thefinregblog/2019/07/09/how-does-the-market-react-when-shareholders-lose-power/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Blog post&lt;/a&gt; about the paper at the FinReg Blog of the Duke Law Global Financial Markets Center&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Director Skill Networks</title>
      <link>https://alicakyol.github.io/project/paper5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 17:30:54 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicakyol.github.io/project/paper5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This study investigates how firms select directors from other company boards. The resource acquisition theory states that firms select directors to gain specific skills and expertise which is missing on a board. In contrast, homophily theory states that firms select directors that fit into the current pool of directors. Our results lend strong support for the latter and show that firms acquire skills that are neither common nor rare, thus lending additional support for board fit. Our findings highlight why many firms have such difficulties in accessing rare director skills. This might have negative implications on how well boards can fulfill their monitoring role within the principal-agent framework of corporate governance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corporate Governance and Fraud</title>
      <link>https://alicakyol.github.io/publication/paper11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 14:12:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicakyol.github.io/publication/paper11/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Director Skill Sets</title>
      <link>https://alicakyol.github.io/publication/paper10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 14:12:10 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicakyol.github.io/publication/paper10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best Paper Award in Corporate Finance in the 2014 FMA Asia Meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortlisted for the Best Paper Award in Corporate Finance in the 2015 FMA Meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://corpgov.law.harvard.edu/2018/08/14/director-skill-sets/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Blog post&lt;/a&gt; about the paper at the Harvard Law School Forum on Corporate Governance and Financial Regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Elimination of Broker Voting in Director Elections</title>
      <link>https://alicakyol.github.io/publication/paper9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 14:12:08 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicakyol.github.io/publication/paper9/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Location, Managerial Entrenchment, and Short-Term Pressure</title>
      <link>https://alicakyol.github.io/project/paper7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 17:31:06 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicakyol.github.io/project/paper7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Prior studies have documented that geographic distance renders remotely located firms more difficult to monitor. This paper asks whether remote firms self-discipline by removing anti-takeover provisions. We find that remote firms are more likely to leave anti-takeover provisions in place, which further enhances managerial entrenchment. Interestingly, this entrenchment does not lead to worse investment decisions by remote firms. In fact, we provide evidence that being out of sight could benefit firms by mitigating short-term pressure from Wall Street.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Regulatory Changes Affect the Underpricing of European IPOs?</title>
      <link>https://alicakyol.github.io/publication/paper8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 14:12:05 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicakyol.github.io/publication/paper8/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Causes and Consequences of Accelerated Stock Repurchases</title>
      <link>https://alicakyol.github.io/publication/paper7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 14:12:03 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicakyol.github.io/publication/paper7/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Chooses Board Members?</title>
      <link>https://alicakyol.github.io/publication/paper6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 14:12:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicakyol.github.io/publication/paper6/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Capital Costs, Firm Leverage, and Unemployment Rates</title>
      <link>https://alicakyol.github.io/publication/paper5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 14:11:58 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicakyol.github.io/publication/paper5/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Share Repurchase Reasons and the Market Reaction to Actual Share Repurchases: Evidence from Australia</title>
      <link>https://alicakyol.github.io/publication/paper4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 14:11:56 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicakyol.github.io/publication/paper4/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shareholders in the Boardroom: Wealth Effects of the SEC’s Rule to Facilitate Director Nominations</title>
      <link>https://alicakyol.github.io/publication/paper3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 14:11:52 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicakyol.github.io/publication/paper3/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Governance Characteristics and the Market Reaction to the SEC’s Proxy Access Rule</title>
      <link>https://alicakyol.github.io/publication/paper2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 14:11:47 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicakyol.github.io/publication/paper2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stock Returns around Non-Trading Periods: Evidence from an Emerging Market</title>
      <link>https://alicakyol.github.io/publication/paper1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicakyol.github.io/publication/paper1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alicakyol.github.io/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicakyol.github.io/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
